# KYLE MANNING DATA ANALYST NASHVILLE, TN | REMOTE

## **ABOUT ME**

An accomplished leader in strategic and operational planning through the application of resource management and practical problem-solving. Experienced in teamwork and adaptive decision-making while managing rapidly evolving projects. Formally educated in data implementation and evaluation through qualitative and quantitative analysis.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL**

## **Data Analyst Apprentice**

Jan 2022 - Present

- Full-time intensive, project management-based training in data analytics using business intelligence and visualization tools for data-driven decision-making
- Hands-on training in SQL, Python, PowerBI, Tableau, and Excel
- Used real-world datasets and projects where findings were presented to stakeholders from the community
- Project management/tracking with Kanban Boards and issue tracking
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and PowerBI

### LOS ANGELES POLICE DEPARTMENT

## Police Officer - Undercover Investigator

Sept 2014 - Jan 2021

- Conducted complex short and long-term investigative projects
- Utilized data analytics for identifying crime trends and patterns for crime prevention and tracking dangerous criminals to enhance public safety
- Coordinated the strategic planning and administration of high-risk operations
- Provided training and mentorship to probationary and junior police officers
- Responded to thousands of service calls requiring adaptive problem-solving

### SPORT SPECIFIC TRAINING

#### Owner/Trainer

Jan 2011 - Sept 2014

- Advanced from trainer to co-owner after one year, and owner after two years
- Increased revenue 50% over two years while involved in business operations which enabled me to achieve my personal goal of funding my college education
- Developed comprehensive client fitness programs for high school, collegiate, and professional athletes through goal-oriented and data-driven processes

## **EDUCATION**

#### NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

**Data Analytics Certification** 

Exp Grad: April 2022

# CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, NORTHRIDGE

Master of Public Administration, Leadership and Management Bachelor of Science, Kinesiology/Biomechanics

## HONORS

- Over (50) Departmental Commendations Los Angeles Police Department
- Four-time recipient of the California Highway Patrol "10851" Award
  - Awarded for high productivity related to self-initiated investigations
- Los Angeles Police Department Academy Squad Leader
- The United States Marine Corps Platoon Leadership Course Squad Leader

### CONTACT



805-551-0474



kylemanning1990@gmail.com



github.com/kyman90



linkedin.com/in/kylemanning1

# SKILLS

- Data Analysis
- Project Management
- SQL
- Leadership
- PowerBI
- Git/GitHub
- Excel
- Problem-Solving
- Python
- Tableau
- · Scrum/Agile Methodologies

## DATA PROJECTS

- <u>AppTrader Startup</u> Applied SQL code to determine the most profitable app investments based on specific business model guidelines
- College/Major Salaries

   Developed an interactive PowerBI dashboard to analyze colleges, college types, region, and majors and how these factors influence median salaries
- Wildland Fire Analysis Utilized an interactive Tableau dashboard to examine United States wildland fires by state, the most common fire causes, and year-over-year trends

## CERTIFICATIONS

- Professional Scrum Master
- Complete SQL Bootcamp 2021 Udemy
- Spreadsheet Fundamentals DataCamp